have you ever wondered if e to the pi or
Pi the E is the larger number here's a
way to figure it out without a
calculator first plot the function y =
1X then plot the x coordinate e and the
x coordinate Pi notice e is less than Pi
we can find the area under this curve
between e and pi as the definite
integral where X ranges from E to Pi of
1x
DX we can also draw this rectangle
living over e to the pi and we see that
the area under the curve is less than
the area of the rectangle which is 1 E *
piun - e according to the fundamental
theorem of calculus the definite
integral is the natural log of Pi - 1
and we can simplify the area of the
rectangle to Pi eus 1 from this we see
that the natural log of Pi is less than
Pi e we can multiply both sides by E and
then apply two natural log rules to see
that Pi the E is less than e to the pi
so using the curve y = 1X we've proved
analytically that pi to the E is less
than e to the pi